（男性アナウンサー）
先ほど発生しました―
The embassy of the eastern trade
東亜連合経済体･極東通商部大使館
占拠事件の現場続報です
of the southeast economic alliance...
Has just been occupied.
11 armed soldiers have taken 42
civilians as hostages.
Major kusanagi, you are a talented professional.
（藤本(ふじもと)）
君こそ理想の人材だ 草薙(くさなぎ)少佐
Thank you, advisor fujimoto.
（素子(もとこ)）ありがとうございます
藤本補佐官
（リチャード）成功は目前だ
クルツ中佐
Success is just one step away, lt. Col. Kurutsu.
（クルツ）
同感です リチャード大使
I agree with you, ambassador Richard.
Talking face to face is just formality.
（藤本）面談は形式にすぎない
The age of government officials
今や人工知能と事務官が
審議を処理する時代だ
working with al has come.
（素子）
この会話も影響するのでは？
Is it okay for us to meet like this?
（藤本）
機械にヒトが萎縮する必要はない
Your team and the government
君の部隊は政府の重要な問題と
合致している
are on the same side on important issues.
The world has been
changing drastically after the war.
（クルツ）大戦が終わり
世界は変化の時期を迎えました
この国も例外ではありません
This country is no exception.
Wars have sped up the development
of cyberbrain and prosthetic bodies.
（藤本）戦争が電脳と
義体開発を加速した
The progress has generated
numberous cybercrimes.
その過程で生まれた
電脳犯罪は深刻だが―
But the is not the essence of the problem.
問題は より本質的だ
The development of cyberbrain and
prosthetic bodies has given rise to...
（クルツ）
電脳と義体ビジネスは―
史上最大の利益追求システムを
生み出しました
Gigantic profit-seeking systems.
リアルタイムで共有される
膨大なデータは―
It is impossible for any country...
もはや世界の どの国家も
管理することは不可能
To manage the huge amount of data
that is shared in real time.
（素子）遠い将来 企業集合体が
国や民族を消し去るとしても―
In future, huge economic alliances
may eliminate countries or races,
but for now, the country still
has its role to perform.
今なお 国家は その役割を
終えてはいない…
Yes, many anarchistic systems are
（藤本）そうだ 特に今―
国際経済の名を借りた
無政府主義的システムの横行は―
causing chaos in the name of trade.
国民の生活保障という
国家の基礎を破壊してしまう
The country's primary role of
protecting its citiizens is jeopardized.
（指揮官）あっ 引けーっ！！
Move back!
（クルツ）電脳と義体は―
Cyberbrain and prosthetic bodies
軍需産業と生活経済の
２つのシステムをつなぐ架け橋
connect the military and the economy.
It's meaningless for the government
to interfere now.
今さら国が規制をすることに
意味はありません
（藤本）
システムを網羅する執行機関が―
People can't say no law-enforcing unit
事実上存在しないからといって―
can monitor all networks...
And break the laws laid forward by the country.
国家が定める法を
超越するわけではない
法を犯すシステムに対しては―
We need to tackle directly...
The people who break the law.
直接的な解決が必要だ
Either we let informatization become the system,
情報化は システムになるか
隷属するかの選択を迫ります
or submit to the system.
What we need now is...
今 必要なのは…
（素子）
システムを裁く 攻性の執行機関
An offensive law-enforcing unit that
can monitor and judge all systems.
A network unified with the system that
システムと一体化し―
ヒトを正しく選別する
ネックワークです
enables people to choose correctly.
我々は君と君の組織を
迎えるべき企業体と認識している
Lt. Col. Kurutsu, we welcome you
and your organization very much.
クルツ中佐
（藤本）政府直下の対テロ活動
An anti-terrorism unit that reports
directly to the government...
最先端の電脳捜査
High-tech investigation of cybercrime,
exposure of commercial crimes...
企業犯罪の告発
君の部隊にタブーはない
There's nothing your team can't do.
Major, are you done yet?
（バトー）まだか 少佐
（素子）あと数分だ
Only a few more minutes. How's the situation?
状況は？
（バトー）
襲撃から１時間 お祭り騒ぎさ
It's already an hour since the attack.
It's as heated up as a carnival here.
クソッ 公安９課のサル部長だ
Damn, it's the old ape from section 9.
（トグサ）９課の荒巻(あらまき)部長が
俺たちに出動を要請したんだろ？
Didn't chief aramaki request us to act?
He wants us to join his section.
（ボーマ）向こうは専属を望んでる
But major likes to work independently.
（パズ）
独立主義の少佐とは合わないさ
（イシカワ）サルが権限を掌握した
That old ape has network authority.
What should we do, major?
どうする 少佐
９課のネットに割り込むか？
Should we hack the network
of section 9?
（素子）
私が交渉する おとなしく待て
I'll talk to him. You wait here quietly.
（藤本）総理は現行の事件の
早期解決を求めている
The prime minister wants to settle
this as soon as possible.
I will give you network authority to do your work.
そして… その権限が今
君に与えられた
Thank you, advisor fujimoto.
ありがとうございます 補佐官
君は この国が好きかね？
Do you like this country?
I like it as much as the drive it has
能力を発揮したいと思えるほどには
given me to use my talents.
フッ… 国は君に愛される努力を
すべきだな
Then the country should
work hard to earn your love.
"Gun shot has been confimed
at the occupied embassy."
では ただちに
I'll go right away.
（藤本）ああ それと…
Wait...
Yes...
Your smile is too perfect.
（藤本）君の笑顔は完璧すぎる
There's no need to isolate the memory
of your prosthetic body like that.
そんなふうに
義体のメモリを割く必要はない
私はプログラムで
笑ったことはありません 補佐官
I've never made a programmed smile,
advisor fujimoto.
フッ… 君の魂を…
ゴーストを疑う気はない
Well... I have no intentions to doubt your ghost.
I'll go to the embassy now.
現場へ向かいます
All the best.
健闘を
Ishikawa, any information?
（素子）
イシカワ インフォメーション
（イシカワ）
国家審議会 第320期―
Our budget is approved in the 320th
予算通過レポートを確認
congress meeting. That's great, major!
やったな 少佐
Come into my cyberbrain.
We need to solve this fast!
（素子）私のロビーへ入れ
事件を取るぞ
草薙…
Kusanagi... I didn't expect to see you here.
こんな所で会うとはな
You are here to kiss the ass of the government?
時代遅れの政府に
尻尾を振りに来たか
And you're here to help greedy
（素子）お前は？
企業の利益追求機械になるのか？
クルツ
businessmen gross more profit?
軍組織の大半が民営化される
Almost half of the military has been privatized.
This is war.
これは戦争だ
負ける側につけば未来はない
The side that loses will be doomed.
The war is over.
戦争は終わった
ゴーストにまでシリアルナンバーを
つけられる気はない
I don't want anyone to engrave a
serial number on my ghost.
ヒトは皆 交換可能な消費単位だ
Humans are all exchangeable consumer commodities.
Very soon we'll know
お前と私のどちらが消耗品か―
which of us is expendable.
すぐ分かる
（素子）
７分で着く 情報そろってるな
I'll be there in 7 minutes.
Have we got all the information?
（イシカワ）国防省の
防衛庁格下げに反発した―
11 soldiers who object to downgrade
国防派軍人11名が―
the ministry of defense (Mod)...
東亜連合経済体･
極東通商部大使館を占拠
Have seized the embassy of eastern
trade of southeast economic alliance.
現在の位置 連中の経歴 関係組織だ
This is the location of the gang,
their past history and related units.
（トグサ）えっと…
（バトー）フンッ
All eleven of them are cyborgs.
（バトー）11名全員が義体化
２名がヘビー級の改造義体だ
Two of them are heavily prosthetized.
機動警察ごときじゃ手は出せねえな
The police tactical unit
won't be able to handle this.
There are 42 hostages, 36 of them are
（パズ）人質は42名
36名は爆弾と一緒にホールで軟禁
detained in the lobby with a bomb.
The other 6 are senior officials
who hid in the panic room.
残り６名はパニックルームに
逃げた幹部で―
そっちが本命だろう
I guess they are the real targets.
（ボーマ）扉が開けば最悪だ
It'll be a disaster if the door is opened.
何百日も籠城か
公開処刑をやらかすか
Either they'll shut themselves inside
the embassy for weeks,
or they'll execute the hostages in public.
（素子）連中の要求は？
What are they asking for?
Maintain the status of the mod
and terminate court-martial.
（トグサ）
国防省の維持と軍事裁判の中止
There's no mention of escape route.
逃走に関するものはなし
They just want a war zone of their own?
（素子）
求めるのは自分勝手な戦場か
私の合図でドミネを実行 突入だ
Follow my command and force a domination.
待ってくれ 俺たちだけで？
Wait. Ls it only us?
（素子）
狙撃に電脳ハックのフォロー付き
After the attack we will follow up with
a hack to their cyberbrains.
The logicomas will be our shield.
盾はロジコマ
周囲の機動隊が敵増援を防ぐ
The police will stop the gang from
getting help. What else do we need?
他に何かいるか？
（トグサ）ん… マジかよ…
Are you serious?
（バトー）
教科書とネクタイがなきゃ―
You can't do anything without
何もできねえか 新米くんは
your necktie and textbook, greenhorn?
You're the only one who's not a cyborg,
（パズ）お前だけ生身はつらいよな
it'll be hard for you to work with us.
この機会に全身義体化したらどうだ
（トグサ）なっ…
Why don't you take this chance to
prosthetize your whole body?
What...?
（ボーマ）死んだら
美人の奥さんに俺が電話してやるよ
If you die,
I'll give your pretty wife a call.
Before your cyberbrain is smashed,
（イシカワ）
電脳を吹っ飛ばされる前に―
遺言くらいは回収してやれるぜ
I'll help to retrieve your last words.
（サイトー）苦しまずに
とどめを刺してほしい時は―
If you wanna die without pain,
俺を呼んでくれよ
remember to let me know.
Stop joking, you guys.
（トグサ）ふざけんな お前ら
いいぜ やってやるさ！
I'll show you guys I can do it!
（素子）お前たちは
私が見つけた最高のパーツだ
You are the best 'parts' I've ever found.
If you don't perform to your best,
パフォーマンスを発揮できないなら
いつでもパージしてやる
I'll just purge you out!
ただし お前たちの大半は―
If I didn't let you stay in my squad,
most of you here will just end up in jail
私の部隊にいない限り
刑務所行きか―
or get stabbed in the back.
誰かに背中を撃たれる運命だ
Don't ever forget this!
それを忘れるな
Get ready to break in!
突入用意だ 配置につけ
She doesn't need to call us 'parts'.
（トグサ）ヒトを部品呼ばわりかよ
（バトー）あれで
ハッパかけてるつもりなんだろ
You want to break in like that?
世間知らずのお姫様は
What a naive Princess.
（ボーマ）鬼だな
She's a demon.
Damn gorilla woman!
（イシカワ）メスゴリラが
（サイトー）ひでえ女だよ
She's the worst!
That's because she really trusts us.
（パズ）
俺たちを信頼してるってことさ
（トグサ）
クソッ マジで殺されるかも
Damn it, we really might be killed.
We can't break in with just our teams.
（荒巻）我々だけでは突入できん！
（荒巻）特殊部隊は？
レンジャーはどうした？
How about the special unit and the ranger team?
（部下）どこも出動を拒否
All of them refused to help.
They don't want to fight their own pals
海外の戦争商売屋のために
同胞を撃ちたくはないと…
for some foreign military businessmen.
What they should do is stop
their pals from sinning further.
これ以上 彼らに
罪を犯させるなと言え
関連する全部隊が
共謀罪に問われるぞ
All the related parties
will be accused as conspirators.
Chief aramaki, please retrieve your men.
部長 交渉人を引き上げて
You have arrived finally, major?
少佐！ やっと来たか
I'm sorry to say this but please
retrieve your men.
（素子）
悪いけど そちらは引いてもらうわ
ほう… 先ほど審議を通った
妙な部隊予算は お前か
So the secret budget that just got
approved is for you?
政治家頼りとは らしくない
Teamming up with politicians is so not like you.
（素子）
面倒だからトップと交渉したの
There's too much bureaucray so I'd
rather talk directly to the top guy.
（荒巻）
総理直属など書類上にすぎん
Working directly under the prime minister
is just some terms on paper.
国際法にのっとった部隊を
お勧めする
I think you'd better set up your squad
in compliance with international laws.
Like a special unit within the int'l
国際救助隊内に創設される
攻殻機動隊…
rescue team as your suggested?
だったかしら？
（荒巻）戦争さえなければ
とっくに成立していた
If it wasn't the war,
i would've set that up already.
事前に犯罪の芽を摘み―
We can stop these incidents from
こうした事件を
起こる前に食い止める
happening if we have such a team.
Let's not talk about a hypothetic unit here.
（素子）せっかくだけど―
空想の部隊より今の事件を取るわ
I'd rather get my job done first.
What is the time of domination?
突入時刻は？
20 seconds later.
（素子）20秒後
なるべく殺さないから―
We don't want to kill,
私たちのあとで働かせてあげる
so please don't act until we have finished.
You guys are like a bunch of kids
playing with a new toy.
まるで おもちゃを
手に入れた子供だな
（素子）ドミネーション実行！
Start the domination.
Communication is lost... our system is dominated.
（兵士）
通信が… ドミネを食らった
Shit! It's an advanced domination.
（改造兵）
上等だ かかってきやがれ！
照準が… 目に侵入されてる！
I can't aim, my eyes are intruded.
ぐうっ… ぐううっ…
うぐっ！ ああっ ぐあああっ！！
（兵士）おい どうした！？
What's going on?
（サイトー）ハァ…
Come on!
Hello!
（ロジコマ）ハロ～
う… クソがっ！
Damn it!
あ… ぐわっ！
（バトー）ロジコマ 人質を守れ
Logicoma, protect the hostages.
（ロジコマたち）
命令は了解されました～
Got it!
So you are my prey?
てめえが俺の獲物か
（兵士）急げ 人質を渡すな！
Quick! Don't let them take the hostages!
We need to do whatever we can to gain time!
何としても時間を稼ぐんだ
Hello!
（ロジコマ）ハロ～
（兵士）おっ
見ろ 俺だって…
I can also do it!
うわっ！ 倒れろよ！
Come on, just fall down!
What are you aiming at? No killing.
（素子）どこ狙ってる 殺すな
Don't monitor my eyesight!
（サイトー）
いちいち視界をのぞくなよ
Please stop your habit of killing.
The war is over.
（素子）殺し癖を直せ
戦争は終わった
There're many dudes who're still continuing.
まだ続けてるやつらばかりだろ
Go to hell!
（兵士）くたばれ！
（ボーマ）ご愁傷様
I feel sorry for you.
（改造兵）ふ～ん！
（バトー）ぐっ…
You're prosthetized for strength only, how absurd.
パワーだけの無茶な改造だな
When you almost died in the war and
then later got prosthetized,
戦場で死にかけて
全身義体になった時―
you must've thought that you've
become the strongest man.
最高の自分になれたと思ったろ
ふんっ
（バトー）俺もそうだったよ
I also thought the same way.
（バトー）
少佐 こっちは終わったぜ
Major, this side is cleared.
How about the panic room?
（素子）パニックルームは？
The door is intact. I see two guys moving.
（イシカワ）扉は無事だ
２名が移動中
（素子）私とバトーで挟み込む
Batou and I will go after them.
You go and release the hostages.
人質を解放
Bring all the captured soldiers to the lobby.
捕らえた連中をホールへ集めろ
Shall we also break in?
（部下）我々も突入しますか？
道化役が望みか？
Do you wanna make yourself a fool?
We just need to be the first one to take
本庁より先に現場検証の主導権を
握れればいい
control of the onsite inspection.
It only takes 7 people to take down a group
200名規模で包囲した相手を
７人に奪われるか…
that is surrounded by 200. Nice!
痛快だな
"Occupation came to a deadlock"
he's alive, Mr. prime minister.
彼は無事です 総理
Hmm... I'll issue an execution order.
（総理大臣）
うむ… 命令書を発行する
（イシカワ）あん？
Batou?
（素子）バトー！？
（バトー）少佐！？
Major? Where is the enemy?
敵はどこだ？
What happened, lshikawa?
（素子）
イシカワ どうなってる！？
There was a moment of interference.
（イシカワ）一瞬だが妨害された
There is a 12th criminal inside the embassy.
12人目が敷地内にいる
（素子）12人目？ 位置を探せ！
A 12th one? Find him now!
Hey!
（バトー）おい！
同士討ち？
Attacking fellow team members?
うっ！ ハァッ！
Get outta here fast!
さあ 早く外へ！
Strange... there should be one more.
（パズ）変だ １人足りない
さっきから通信にノイズが…
There's some noise just now...
おっ… ちょっと触らないで！
Hey, don't touch that!
（イシカワ）人質に電脳汚染！
The hostages are infected!
このパターンは…
This pattern...
（素子）疑似記憶ウイルス…
A false memory virus...
It's the fire starter!
Distribute the vaccine quickly!
ファイア･スターターだ！
仮想ワクチンを流せ！
（バトー）ゴーストロックを
かけたんじゃねえのか！？
Didn't we activate their ghost locks?
Why can they still move?
なんで動ける！？
（イシカワ）12人目だ いたぞ！
It's the 12th person!
（素子）
そいつがパッケージ化された
ウイルスのホストだ！
He's the source of the packaged virus.
電脳を破壊しろ！
Destroy his cyberbrain quickly!
I haven't got a permit to kill for a long time!
久々だぜ 殺しの許可は
Please wait, Mr. prime minister.
お待ち下さい 総理！
耳が！ 俺の生身のパーツを！
My ear!
My ear is real! I'm so gonna kill you!
ぶっ殺してやるっ！
何てこった…
What happened?
疑似電脳…
Virtual cyberbrain...
It's a remote controlled puppet without a ghost.
ゴーストのねえ遠隔操作の人形だ
（素子）12人目の位置は？
Where is the 12th person?
（イシカワ）見失った 今 捜してる
I lost him. I'm searching again.
（イシカワ）
政府の緊急事態警報？
Emergency warning issued by the government?
Secret meeting at the yagasaki hotel? Bomb attack?
矢ケ崎(やがさき)ホテルで秘密会談？
爆弾テロ？
What's this about? Who's dead?
何の話だ？ 誰が死んだ？
（男性アナウンサー）
現職の総理大臣が暗殺される―
It's the first time in our history that the
current prime minister is murdered.
前代未聞の事件は―
At the same time, the embassy of the
southeast economic alliance is taken.
我が国の兵士が
東亜連合大使館を占拠する…
Are the murder of the prime minister
（男性アナウンサー）
大使館占拠と―
総理暗殺の因果関係は
不明とのことで―
and the embassy occupation related?
捜査当局は辞任した
国防大臣に代わり―
The investigating unit has requested
臨時代行として
北原(きたはら)要子(ようこ)国防副大臣に…
vice-minister of defense kitahara to...
（女性アナウンサー）
内閣は防衛庁格下げを―
強行すると見られ
軍人会と反発を強めています
Now look who is expendable...
どっちが消耗品？
Someone has disposed of you after using you?
誰かに使い捨てにされたの？
I'll dig him out and put
そいつを捜し出して
お前の横で眠らせるわ クルツ
his body next to yours, kurutsu.
（荒巻）秘密会談の相手は
極東通商部のリチャード大使だ
The secret meeting was held with
ambassador Richard of eastern trade.
同時刻に起きた大使館占拠の背景を
予断なく分析しろ
Analyze the background of the
embassy occupation thoroughly.
Yes sir.
（公安９課員）はっ
（荒巻）総理官邸の動きを洗え
Investigate the prime minister's official
residence thoroughly.
不逮捕特権を主張する者には
監視をつけろ
Monitor those who plan to exercise
their privilege from arrest.
（公安９課員）はっ
Yes sir.
これが起こる前に―
I should have done something...
何としても食い止めねば
ならなかったのだ！
To stop all these from happening.
（素子）メンテは終わったか
Is maintenance over?
予算があるとメンテも充実だな
If we have a generous budget,
we can have better maintenance.
（ボーマ）総理が死んじまって
次の予算が下りるか不安だがな
Now that the pm is dead,
are we going to get our next budget?
調整に２時間くれ
Gimme two hours to fix my body.
俺を撃ったやつの眉間を
ぶち抜いてやる
I'll kill the guy
who hit me!
（イシカワ）
少佐の同型義体を追えよ サイトー
Saito, search for cyborgs that
are the same model as major.
見たのは お前だけだぜ
You're the only one who's seen him.
（サイトー）両方やってやる
I'll do both.
（パズ）で どうする 少佐？
What should we do now, major?
Paz, go to the embassy.
Borma, go to the explosion site.
（素子）パズは大使館
ボーマは爆破現場だ
両面作戦だったか検証しろ
Check if these two incidents are connected.
（バトー）
クルツ中佐たちの電脳は？
How about the cyberbrains
of kurutsu and the others?
They're severly damaged. No data can be retrieved.
（素子）損傷が激しくて読めない
あいつの件とウイルスは
私が調べる
I'll investigate her and the virus.
If the cyborg really did spread
（サイトー）ウイルスを流したのが
少佐の同型義体だとして―
the virus, can I kill him?
殺(や)っていいのか？
（素子）
死体が黒幕の情報を吐くか？
Can a dead person talk?
殺し癖を直せ バカ
Stop your habit of killing, idiot!
（バトー）
で 俺と新米くんが実行犯か
Should I investigate the soldiers
with the greenhorn?
If we waste more time here,
セオリーじゃ海外へ逃亡済みだぜ
they might have excaped overseas already.
If the enemy's goal is political,
（パズ）内政干渉が目的なら
敵は国内の機関に潜ってる
they must've infiltrated into the government.
すぐには動けん
They won't act immediately.
（ボーマ）その場合―
So a third party is planning this
国防派軍人を操り
始末した第三者がいるわけか
and manipulating the pro-mod soldiers?
（イシカワ）
同じ国の人間じゃないことを祈るぜ
I hope they're not from this country.
同胞殺しは うんざりだ
I hate killing my own people.
（素子）関係者の背景を洗え
Check the background of all
the people who are related.
くだらんスパイ合戦に
足を取られるな
I don't wanna lose the race
of gathering information.
（素子）藤本補佐官…
Advisor fujimoto...
I came to assist in the
DNA check of the dead body.
（藤本）
遺体のＤＮＡ検査で来たんだ
They cannot tell if it's my father
from the appearance of the corpse.
外見では もう父とは
分からないから
必ず犯人を見つけ出します
I will find out the person behind this.
ひどく混乱して―
I'm really confused. I can't even recall
聴取されても昨日のことすら
思い出せないんだ
what happened yesterday.
I don't even remember
父と最後に どんな会話をしたかも
what I last said to my father.
私も経験があります 戦場で
I have experienced the same thing at the war field.
Did you remember in the end?
（藤本）君は思い出せた？
すべてを
Yes, I recalled everything,
and never forget about them.
二度と忘れません
It seems that my father had sent me
（藤本）父は死の寸前―
私に何かの命令書を発行した
an execution order before he died.
But it was intercepted by someone.
だが何者かに
ジャミングされてしまった
Can you help me to find out
頼む
父が最後に
何を託そうとしていたか…
what my father had asked me to do?
教えてほしい
（藤本）ああ それと…
（素子）あっ…
And also...
Hmm?
Would you care to have dinner with me?
一緒に食事でも どうかな？
Huh?
I want to talk to you more, if you don't mind.
また話したい 君さえよければ
私が入れる店は限られます
The number of restaurants that
welcome me is very limited.
（素子）聞いていたな イシカワ
Did you hear it, lshikawa?
（イシカワ）ああ 裏を取る
Yes, I'll go check about it.
（バトー）その男もマークするか？
Should we also follow that guy?
（素子）余計なことはせず
実行犯のネットをつかめ
Stop doing unnecessary things.
Dig out the criminals' network.
父親が吹っ飛んだ翌日に
女を口説くか？
Flirting with woman the next day
his old pal got blasted?
しかも少佐だぜ？
And it's major, not any woman.
Maybe he has always liked her.
もともと気があったんだろ？
（バトー）は～あ
The 3rd generation of a congressman
（トグサ）議員３世の
ボンボンの周囲には―
いないタイプだろうからな
（バトー）フンッ
doesn't get to meet women like major.
それより仕事しようぜ 先輩
Let's just focus on work.
せっかくの権限だ
Now that we've got network authority.
We haven't seen any moving
humans in 900 hours already.
（ツムギ１）
動く人間は900時間ぶりだ
I've heard of the privatization of unit 501.
（素子）501機関の民営化は
聞いていたけど―
無人工場になる予定とはね
But I don't know it's been transformed
into an automated factory.
Everyone has switched to work for harimadara.
（ツムギ１）
皆 ハリマダラ社に移籍した
用件は？ 工場見学かね？
What's your matter?
Did you come for a factory tour?
クルツは なぜ現場にいたの？
Why was kurutsu at the site of the explosion?
（ツムギ２）
利益と生き残りのためだ
For profit and survival.
リチャード大使と総理は―
Richard and the pm have agreed to
義体開発のデッドエンド回避で
合意していた
slow down the development of...
Prosthectic technology, just to prolong
（ツムギ１）
技術更新を意図的に遅らせ―
生産ラインを延命させるために
the life span of the production lines.
The country's been financing research
（素子）
開発の行き詰まりを避けるため―
to avoid the deadend, hasn't it?
研究予算を国が出すのではないの？
（ツムギ２）
逆だ 現行の多くの義体が―
Exactly the opposite. A lot of prosthetic
bodies that we use now...
次世代では
バージョンアップ不能となる
Cannot be upgraded in the next generation.
Different from you who have been
prosthetized since 0 year old.
ゼロ歳児の全身義体だった
君と違って
Your prosthetic body was designed
with the possibility of version upgrade.
君は成長を前提に開発された
設計者である草薙博士の慧眼(けいがん)だな
Owing to the wisdom of the designer Dr. kusanagi.
（素子）
で… ここでパーツを造るの？
So this is where you manufactured the parts?
Yes, for the sake of our survival.
（ツムギ１）
我々の命を保つためのね
（ツムギ２）
技術温存は既得権益の延命
Decelerating technology development to
strengthen the vested interests.
Or innovating technology
to seize huge market shares.
技術革新は
巨額のシェア独占を意味する
クルツは前者に賭け
後者のシステムに抹殺された
Kurutsu believed in the former
and got erased by interest parties of the latter.
犯人にとって 総理と大使を
同時に暗殺する―
So the culprit has huge incentives to
kill both the pm and the ambassador?
十分な動機があるわけね
Thanks for the information.
教えてくれてありがとう
（ツムギ１）
ご両親に挨拶するといい
Go say "hi" to your parents.
I'll do it next time.
（素子）またにするわ
（ツムギ２）いつでも来たまえ
Just come any time.
彼らは私たちと同じで―
Like us, your parents aren't going anywhere.
ここを動かない
Kouichi sawada, ex-communication
soldier in the army panzer division.
（トグサ）澤田(さわだ)功一(こういち)
元陸軍機甲師団通信兵
Someone who manages the military
network has to live in a place like this?
軍人ネットの管理者がこんな所に？
（バトー）
実行犯の電脳に残っていた―
Yes, if the records left in the cyberbrains
アクセス記録が確かならな
of the criminals are true.
（バトー）ロジコマ
Logicoma
according to the temperature sensor,
there's only one person inside.
（ロジコマ）熱探知は１人です
（トグサ）誰も死んでないか？
Anyone dead?
（ロジコマ）探査が不十分です
I can't detect that.
（バトー）死人は何も語らねえ
A dead person won't talk.
If he's not alive, we'll have to start
our investigation from scratch.
生きててくれねえと
振り出しに戻っちまうな
What a group of noisy visitors.
（澤田）物騒な客だな
ドアくらい閉めろ
Can't you just keep the door closed?
ハァ… フゥ…
（澤田）誰か話をしに
来るかもしれないのでな
Because I have a gut feeling that
someone will come to talk to me.
何か お求めかね？
What do you want to know?
（トグサ）澤田功一さんですね
特務隊の者です
Are you kouichi sawada? We're from
a special squad of the government.
総理暗殺の件で
お伺いしたいことが
We would like to ask you something
about the murder of the pm.
何のデータだ
What information do you want?
兵士たちの遺言だ
The last words of the soldiers who are involved.
相続財産もなく―
These soldiers don't have anything
ただ最期の言葉を送ってくる
to leave behind except their last words.
After they die,
自らの命を絶ったあと
友人も家族もいないせいで―
since they have no friends or relatives,
their last words are sent to me,
面識もない事務管理者の私に
自動送信でな
an officer whom they have never met.
If only they can come and tell me
their last words in person.
せめて話をしに来ればいいものを…
Is somebody dead?
（ロジコマ）誰か死んでますか～？
（バトー）ここじゃないどこかでな
Not in here. You wait for us outside.
戻るまで待機しろ
（ロジコマ）は～い
Roget
any message that seems connected
to the murder of the prime minister?
（トグサ）総理暗殺を
におわすものが来たことは？
（澤田）一度もない
No, but the last words of those
大使館を占拠した者たちの
遺言ならあるが
who occupied the embassy have come.
Anyone gone missing?
消息が途絶えた者は？
（澤田）大勢いる
リストを転送しよう
A lot. Let me send you the name list.
（バトー）
号令をかけそうな人物は？
Is there anyone who looks like a leader?
（澤田）さて…
The most influential among the list
影響力なら 灘(なだ) 晴良(はるよし)陸軍大佐だ
would be army col. Haruyoshi nada.
北原副大臣の意見役だが
事件の前に姿を消した
He's the advisor of vice-minister
of defense kitahara.
But he has gone missing before the incidents.
You can come and tell me your last words.
君も せめて話をしに来てくれよ
なんで俺が？
Why?
（澤田）自決者の大半は全身義体だ
Most of those who end their lives are
電脳の規格が変わり
新しい義体が使えず―
full cyborgs.
As the spec of the cyberbrain changes
生きながら朽ちてゆく
they can't switch to new prosthetics.
What?
私のように…
Just like me.
中継人の役目がなければ
私も自分を始末していた
If I don't have this job,
I would have killed myself already.
電脳のバージョン選択と
時代の変化が食い違ったが最後―
You can only choose to upgrade your cyberbrain,
or get left behind by the change in technology.
これが義体化の末路だ
This is the deadend of prosthetics development.
How about the dead person?
（ロジコマ）
死んだ人はどうしました？
There's nothing we can do to help.
（トグサ）どうしようもなかったよ
（ロジコマ）修理が不可能なら
データの回収と復旧を推奨します
If the body can't be fixed,
I suggest data retrieval and system restoration.
If the person is dead,
you can't restore its ghost or anything.
（トグサ）死んだら 命も
ゴーストも復旧できねえの
（ロジコマ）
不便なユニットですね～
It seems like a very inconvenient unit.
Mr. batou, have you been dead before?
バトーさんは
死んだことがありますか
I almost died
そのはずだったが
全身義体になっちまったのさ
but then I got my whole body prosthetized.
（ロジコマ）バトーさんが
少佐のパーツとして働くのは―
Do you work for major as a 'part'
because you want to die?
死ぬためですか？
Hey...
俺みたいないい男は
なかなか死なねえの
A good man like me doesn't die easily,
分かった？
understand?
（ロジコマ）
はい いつも貴重な学習経験を―
Yes. Thank you for your teaching.
ありがとうございます
（ロバート）
外務省を通じて要請しろ
Make a request through the
ministry of foreign affairs (Mfa).
We are victims. We object to hiding
我々は被害者だ
犯人の軍属抹消など認めんぞ
the military identity of the criminals.
（ロバート）政府に賠償を要求する
We will request for a compensation
from the government.
（パズ）厄介な被害者ですね
He looks more like a trouble maker than a victim.
（荒巻）
ロバート･リー極東通商部代表…
Robert Lee, representative of the eastern trade.
悪名高いフィクサーだ
He's a notorious fixer.
Upon the request of the us,
he was once sent into exile.
かって米国の要請で
国外追放されかけたが―
But somehow he made his way back into the country.
あのとおり抜け目なく
切り抜けおった
また襲撃されるかもしれないのに
いい度胸です
He might be attacked again
but he seems not to care.
露見しては不都合なことが
多いのだろう
I bet he has a lot of things to hide.
総理の秘密会談を
誰がセッティングしたか―
I want to know who set up the secret
meeting for the prime minister.
知りたいところだ
誰が会談場所を漏えいしたかも
Maybe the place of the meeting
was leaked by someone.
合同捜査は いつでも歓迎する
少佐に伝えておけ
Please tell major she is welcome
to join hands with us in investigating.
（雨形(あまがた)）電脳や義体同様
企業にとって規格とは国境だ
The spec of cyberbrain and prosthetics
are like borders of a country.
Although the borders will create
differences among the countries,
国の境目が
格差を生むからといって―
国境を放棄する国はない
no country will give up its own borders.
（雨形）クルツ中佐と私は―
Lt. Col. Kurutsu and I were searching
ネクスト･エポックの道を
模索していた
for the way to the next generation.
国境を越えるシステムで
利益を生んできたのは―
Councillor amegata, you've been
reaping profits from cross-border trade.
あなた方では？ 雨形審議官
I'm not a councillor anymore.
元審議官だ
Lt. Col. Kurutsu once said,
中佐にも言われたよ
いつか電脳ネットが―
one day, the cyberbrain network will
cross the borders of enterprises.
企業の境目すら
越える日が来るだろうと
This can be something in the far future.
遠い未来の話だ
If you think you'll be in danger,
危険があるとお考えなら
我々の保護と監視をお勧めします
we can send someone to protect you.
それには及ばない
There's no need.
君の元同僚たちが我が社を守る
Your ex-colleagues will protect me and my company.
（イシカワ）少佐
Major.
（素子）情報 出たか
What have you got?
（イシカワ）
ジャミングのほうは まだだ
I still haven't found out who
intercepted the pm's execution order.
そのかわり クルツ中佐の
データ転送を発見した
But I know lt. Col. Kurutsu
has sent out some data.
The data was sent one minute after
the explosion automatically.
爆発の１分後 外部の自動送信だ
軍人ネットの遺言じゃなく
別の施設だ
It's not like the last words of a soldier.
It's sent to another place.
（素子）住所を送れ 私が行く
Give me the address, I'll go right away.
（素子）501機関員が
そろって企業の従業員？
The members of unit 501 are all
working for large enterprises now?
Or you've all become subjects of research?
それとも研究材料？
（イバチ）手を引いてくれ 草薙
Stop your investigation, kusanagi.
Instructor ibachi...
イバチ教官…
（イバチ）
クルツの件は我々が背負う
We will take care of kurutsu's case.
Stop messing with this!
お前はこれ以上 手を出すな
（ライゾー）
開発機関もなく―
You don't even have backup
自己改造を
繰り返すだけのはぐれ者が
in prosthetic maintenance, loner!
余計なマネをすれば
今度こそ始末するぞ
If you continue to do stupid things,
you'll be dead.
Beware of the ex-members of unit 501
（素子）ハリマダラ社の
元501機関員をマークだ
who're now working for harimadara.
捜査妨害に注意しろ
They might interfere with our investigation.
（イシカワ）
了解 連中も報復する気だろうしな
Okay. I think they'd be
very keen on taking revenge.
デッドエンド回避策だが
政府の資料にあった
We found govt documents on avoiding
deadends in prosthetic development.
20年以上前―
20 years ago, the government
had started a discussion on this.
同じ国策を講じた際の
状況をもとに―
And there was even a security
plan related to this discussion.
警備計画が立てられている
（素子）警備？ 何があった？
Security plan? What happened?
（イシカワ）
行方不明のオンパレードだ
A large scale search for a missing couple.
筆頭は義体研究の博士と
妊娠中だった妻で―
A doctor who's doing prosthetic research
and his pregnant wife.
最後に確認されたのは
化学兵器の事故現場らしい
At last they're found in the accident
scene of some chemical weapons.
Their corpses were kept in a
government institution for research.
遺体は研究のため
どこかの機関が保存…
Are you listening, major?
聞いてるか 少佐
（素子）はっ！
Send the data to my al for further analysis.
（素子）
データを私のＡＩに分析させる
今の事件との関連を洗え
Check if that's related to the two incidents.
（管理人）
所属が変わったそうですね
You belong to a different section now?
Besides the military, we're having more
visitors from the private sector.
最近は軍以外の
企業訪問も増えています
We need to bring up children with
a wider range of skills and talents.
育てる人材の幅も広くなりました
These children are good deals
for enterprises, right?
（素子）企業には いい買い物？
It's a good thing we can secure
the future for these children.
（管理人）子供たちに
未来を約束できるということです
That way.
あちらです
（クリス）こんにちは
Hello.
こんにちは あなたの名前は？
Hello. What is your name?
（クリス）クリス
Chrissy.
Lam motoko kusanagi. I used to live here.
私は草薙素子
昔 ここにいたわ
Do you miss this place?
（クリス）懐かしいと思いますか？
Yes. I recall a lot of things that happened here.
そうね いろいろと思い出すわ
Do you know kurutsu?
クルツを知っているの？
We all know her.
（クリス）みんな知ってる
She's the one who promised
to create a future for us,
ここの子たちの未来を創る人
でも死んでしまった
but she's dead now.
メッセージを共有してもいい？
Can you share her message with me?
Yes.
（クルツ）これを お前たちが
見ているということは―
When you see this message,
もう私という存在は
この世にないということだ
I'm no longer in this world.
Confirm in your own network about the rights
委託される
権利 財産 義務については―
and obligations I entrusted you.
各自のネットで確認しろ
I know you will feel anxious,
but I assure you that we have a future.
不安だろうが未来はある
If you believe in the third world,
第三世界を信じるなら
いつか再会できるだろう
we will meet again some day.
The third world is...
第三世界？
A world without people and material,
a world with data only.
（クリス）
ヒトでもモノでもないデータの世界
もし義体を交換できなくなって―
She said even if we can't change to
newer prosthetic bodies...
And therefore cannot live anymore,
we will still have a place to go to.
それ以上
生きられないとしても―
行ける場所があるって
あなたは信じる？
Do you believe in it?
I'm not sure...
私には分からない…
メッセージはこれだけ？
This is the whole message?
Yes, will I see you again?
また会える？
そうね また会いましょう
Yes, let's meet again.
（トグサ）よっと
（素子）なぜ会って話す？
Why do we have to talk face to face?
私の電脳ロビーじゃ
枝がつくとでも？
You think my cyber lobby is not safe?
いえ… 電脳越しじゃなく
飯食いながら話すとか…
I think chatting over meals is as important
as talking in the cyber lobby.
大事でしょ？
What are you saying?
何を言ってる？
（バトー）統一規格のチームに―
You're the one who brought this guy
あえて生身のこいつを入れたのは
お前だぜ
with flesh and blood into our team!
（バトー）
お前が実はロボットなんじゃ
ないかと心配なんだよ
The greenhorn is worrying if you're just a robot.
新米くんは
（トグサ）うっ…
そこまで言ってねえよ
I didn't say that. I'm just trying
俺はただ 理解と信頼を…
to build up trust and understanding.
（バトー）休暇もなきゃ遊びもねえ
He complained about not having leave
春なのに花見もねえ
ひでえ職場だと
and not having sakura viewing parties.
I didn't say that!
言ってねえって
（バトー）フンッ
あの… 国防派ですが―
It's about the pro-mod gang...
実行犯11名と 灘大佐および
行方不明の７名が―
Similar last words have been
sent out from the 11 criminals,
colonel nada and the seven missing soldiers.
同じ文面の遺書を流してました
Chances are they're all hiding
（バトー）全員潜伏中で―
and waiting to strike again.
次の行動を起こす
可能性大ってわけだ
We only found something strange
で 灘大佐の遺書にだけ
妙な一文があった
in the last words of colonel nada.
“第三世界からの贈り物を
受け取った”と
He said he had received
a gift from the third world.
大佐が例のウイルスを―
Does it mean colonel nada
ブローカーから
入手したという意味では…
has got the virus from the broker?
No... but it's really strange.
（素子）いや… 妙だ
Hmm?
The third world? Ls it some kind of a myth?
（イシカワ）
第三世界… オカルト話の？
（素子）国防省や関連企業で―
Check if anyone in the mod or related
enterprises uses the same term.
Damn it. We need more people in the team.
同じフレーズを使う者が
いないか調べろ
（イシカワ）
クソ 人員を増やしてくれ
I will add more people,
（素子）最適なパーツがいればな
if I can find the right 'parts'.
（イシカワ）
またパーツ呼ばわりかよ
You are calling people 'parts' again.
（素子）何か問題が？
What's the problem?
（イシカワ）新入りが言ってたぜ
This greenhorn once said,
人をモノ呼ばわりする
最低の隊長だって
what kind of a team leader
would call her teammates 'parts'?
（トグサ）えっ…
そこまで言ってませんって！
What? I didn't say that.
（サイトー）報告だぜ 少佐
I have something to report, major.
押収されたライフルと
現場の痕跡から推測するに―
After examining the rifles used by the criminals
狙撃手はＲＭＣ
and the bullet trace,
ヒトじゃなく
リモート機銃で撃ちやがった
it is certain that the snipers
shot with remote machine guns.
（イシカワ）狙撃にウイルス
義体の遠隔操作を全部 独りでか
The same person is attacking
with the virus and controlling the cyborgs?
少佐と同型というより
少佐そのものだな
This isn't a cyborg that is the same model as major.
This is major!
（サイトー）ますます殺意が湧くぜ
I'm getting excited for some killing.
あと さっきから熱い視線を
感じるんだがな
By the way, I feel like someone's
stalking me and staring at me.
（ボーマ）奇遇だな
I also feel the same.
俺もだ
（トグサ）実は こっちも
So do I.
（バトー）９課のサル部長か？
Is it the old ape from section 9?
No, it doesn't feel like him.
（素子）いや 感じが違う
（ボーマ）
関係がありそうなものを発見した
I found someone who's related to the incidents.
おもしろいもん見せてやるから
俺のロビーに入ってくれ
I have something interesting to show you.
Get into my cyber lobby.
何を見せようってんだ？
What do you want to show us?
爆発による物体の移動を
鑑識のサーチをもとに再現した
I did a research on the movement of
objects caused by the explosion,
（ボーマ）
パイロ･リバース･メジャーメント
by a tool called pyro-reverse measurement.
爆発の逆再生だ
It's like a reverse play-back of the explosion.
（トグサ）すげえな
This is really cool!
The case that contains the bomb
has a fingerprint recognition system.
（ボーマ）爆弾入りのケースは
指紋認証式だ
総理と側近以外 開けない
Only the prime minister and those
who are close to him can open it.
（トグサ）監視カメラ？
How about the surveillance camera?
（ボーマ）
軍用だが送信範囲は限られる
It's military equipment but the
transmission range is very limited.
試しにランダムでノイズを送った
I tried to send in random noise.
It uses a cheap cipher circuit operated by al.
（イシカワ）ＡＩ任せの
ちゃちな暗号回線だなあ
I got connected to the network of the peeking man.
のぞき野郎のネットにつながったぜ
（監視者たち）うっ ハァ ハァッ…
What is your name and department?
所属と姓名を言え
Our hitman can't wait to kill, you know.
うちの殺し屋が撃ち殺したくて
ウズウズしてるぞ
（監視者）ぐっ… 条約審議部
セクションＤだ 問い合わせろ！
I belong to section d of treaty deliberation.
（トグサ）公安の外務省出向だぞ
Sent by the police to the mod?
（ボーマ）
総理の秘密会談の関係者か？
Who's involved in the
prime minister's secret meeting?
（秋山(あきやま)）ん…
条約審議部
セクション･リーダーの秋山だ
I'm akiyama from treaty deliberation.
Please explain to us briefly.
手短に説明して
A month ago, we found this guy
（秋山）ひと月前 姿を捉えた
who sells the fire starter.
洗脳 ゴースト侵入 疑似記憶
The virus that can brainwash,
initiate ghost infiltration
and create false memory simultaneously.
実現不能とされた
トリプル･パッケージ･ウイルス…
ファイア･スターターの売り手だ
A triple packaged virus that
makes the impossible possible.
ウイルスと同じ名を名乗る
イカレ野郎さ
That person uses the same name as the virus.
You approached him to get the virus
but got tricked in the end.
ウイルスを手に入れようとして
近づき ハメられた
で 同じ義体の私に監視をつけた
So you decided to spy on me,
a cyborg with the same model?
道化ね
（秋山）あんたは
超ウィザード級ハッカーだ
You are a super-wizard-class hacker.
疑わないほうがどうかしている
It'd be strange not to suspect you.
操られたのはオフィサー２人だ
Two officials were manipulated by the enemy.
Officials?
（素子）オフィサー？
総理の既定路線を
実現するための協力者で―
Their help was needed to execute
the prime minister's plan.
１人は灘 晴良大佐だ
One of them is col. Haruyoshi nada.
（バトー）事件前に消えた大佐か
The colonel that went missing
before the incidents?
（秋山）彼の役目は―
His role is to isolate the radical
国防派の過激分子を
孤立させることだった
group that supports the mod.
But suddenly he's attacking both sides.
なのに突然 両面同時テロの
引き金を引いた
I can only say that his character
has changed suddenly.
人格が変貌したとしか思えん
（素子）ウイルスに感染した
He's infected with the virus.
ブローカーが そこまでやるものか
Does a broker need to do all that for a deal?
総理の敵が高値をつけて
ウイルスを買ったな
The enemy of the pm must have
paid a huge amount for the virus.
（秋山）そいつらの正体を暴き
ブローカーともども掌握したい
I want to dig out who they are,
and also the broker.
もう１人のオフィサーは？
Who is the other official?
国防省 北原要子副大臣
Vice-minister of defense kitahara.
（北原）
あっ… な 何のつもりですか？
What do you want to do?
Don't move!
（桑原(くわはら)）動くな！
組織無視のクズどもが！
You bunch of crap who don't
respect rules and systems.
違法捜査の疑いで逮捕するぞ！
I'll arrest you for illegal investigation.
よさんか
Stop it!
まさか… こんなことが…
I did"£ think it will turn out like this...
（荒巻）話を聞こう
Let's have a talk.
（荒巻）灘大佐から感染し
国防派の暴発を誘導
So she got infected via col. Nada
and led the pro-mod gang to start a riot.
防衛庁格下げと数千人の兵の
リストラのための世論操作か…
All for getting media support
to downgrade the mod and...
Sacking thousands of soldiers?
総理暗殺への関与は？
Is this related to the death of the pm?
今のところなしよ
No as of now.
総理殺害のために―
Officials of the mod and mfa were
国防省中枢と外務省の部隊が
利用されたか…
manipulated in the murder of the pm?
ウイルス自体は見つかっていない
The virus is still not located.
If this woman is behind this...
この女の工作だとしたら…
The hacking route of the cyberbrain is specified.
電脳の侵害ステージから特定した
The victim is also aware.
被害者の自覚もある
私の自作自演という振り付けは
誰のものだ
Who dares to say this is some act that
i put up and perform by myself?
何だと…
What?
彼 ９課じゃないわね
He's not from section 9, right?
情報部戦略室長の桑原だ
He's the head of the
strategy department of intelligence.
お前と うり二つのブローカーを
追っている
He's also chasing the broker of the virus.
（桑原）荒巻！
Aramaki!
So intelligence has paid more than
（素子）つまり情報部が
審議部より高値をつけて―
treaty deliberation to get the virus?
ウイルスを買った組織？
審議部の件は知らん
We don't know anything about treaty deliberation.
購入は逮捕のための偽装で
ウイルス確保の前に逃げられた
We faked the deal to catch the broker,
but lost him before getting the virus.
そういうことにしてあげるわ
If that's how you want to tell the story.
（荒巻）今は あらゆる人員の
協力が不可欠だ
We need all the help we can get now.
突っ張らんで我々と組め 少佐
Major, join hands with us.
保身のため
証人を確保する組織こそ―
Those who protect themselves by
犯人と一緒に裁かれるべきよ
detaining the witness is also as guilty.
この成り上がりの独走部隊が！
You loner and your team stop being so arrogant!
（素子）
突入する時は声をかけるわ
We'll let you know when we break in.
終わったあとで働かせてあげる
You can take on after we finish.
（ロバート）例の部隊が
北原副大臣にたどり着いたぞ
Fire starter, the "team" has
found its way to kitahara.
ファイア･スターター
Your virus is good enough to sweep
those trouble makers away, right?
（伊東(いとう)）君のウイルスで
あの厄介な連中を乗っ取れんのかね
（ニセ素子）焦る必要ないわ
Don't worry. Treaty deliberation and intelligence
審議部も情報部も手の内だし―
are both under our control.
真実こそ最大のワナであり
悲劇なのだから
And the truth is the biggest scandal
国家への忠誠を逆手に取るだけでは
万全と言えん
and tragedy this country's ever seen.
Is it really safe to bet on their
loyalty to the country?
（伊東）我々にたどり着く
いかなる可能性も消すべきだ
Don't let them find us.
報酬は弾んでもらうわよ
Then I'll need a bigger reward.
草薙素子…
Motoko kusanagi... maybe some day
I'll snatch this name for my own use.
いつ名前を奪おうかしらね
（素子）
爆破テロにあった藤本総理が―
It is certain that the pm had sent out
何らかの命令書を
出したことは確かだ
an execution order before the blast.
そして そこからつながる
唯一の線―
The only connection to this is...
北原副大臣の記憶から
浮かんだのが―
A deserted ship in the memory of
vice-minister of defense kitahara.
新浜(にいはま)沖にいる船籍不明の幽霊船だ
It's docked at the Newport pier,
and the owner of the ship is unknown.
（バトー）灘大佐たちの隠れ家…
Although this is the secret hideout
of col. Nada and his gang,
…のわりに情報部に動きはない
surprisingly intelligence seems to
審議部の言うとおり
大佐も汚染されているとすれば…
know nothing about it.
Maybe col. Nada was infected just
as treaty deliberated said.
（パズ）十中八九 ワナだろうな
This is 90% a trap.
（ボーマ）船の航跡と
海底ケーブルの集積箇所が一致
The sailing route of the ship coincides
with the layout of undersea cables.
情報収集艦かもな
This could've been a spy ship for
collecting intelligence.
（イシカワ）情報部に
副大臣を奪われたせいで―
Intelligence has detained kitahara
情報はこれだけだ
so this is all the info we got. What to do?
どうする？
Let's seize the ship and find out.
（素子）制圧して判明させる
フゥ… とことん突撃かよ
What? Sudden attack?
（素子）
疑問があるなら部隊を抜けろ
If you have any doubts you can leave the team.
すべては総理に つながっている
All these are related to the murder
of the prime minister.
真実にたどり着くか
今 ここで降りるか…
Do you want to find out the
truth or give up here?
お前たちのゴーストに従え
Follow your ghost.
Is it not a place smeared with blood?
血まみれの戦場でも
どん詰まりの死に場所でもない
Nor a place leading to death?
新しい生き場所があるんだろ
Is the place you're heading for gonna
お前の進む先に
give us a living place?
少なくとも―
At least we're gonna get
the position we deserve.
私たちに ふさわしい立場を
手に入れるつもりよ
（荒巻）
待機だ 何が出るか分からん
Stand-by here. I dunno what will happen.
Many talk about an independent
最優先ラインの攻性部隊…
口にする者は多いが―
offensive unit with top priority.
None has succeeded in setting up one so far.
実現できた者はいなかったな
今までは…
（サイトー）艦外に人影無し
There's no one outside the ship.
（サイトー）来るぞ！
It's coming!
（ロジコマ）あわわっ…
Where does the tank come from?
（バトー）いきなり戦車かよ！
（イシカワ）
やっぱ来るんじゃなかったぜ
We shouldn't have come here!
Saito!
サイトー！
（サイトー）捕捉できねえぞ！
I can't get it!
Damn it!
（イシカワ）クソッ
It's thermal optical camouflage model 2092,
2902型 熱光学迷彩…
京(きょう)レ製の最新版だ
latest version from kyoren.
（バトー）どれだけ資金がありゃ
戦車と歩兵の分までそろうんだ
How much capital do you need to
have your own tanks and troops?
（素子）船を奪う 援護しろ！
I'm gonna seize control of the ship, cover me!
どうやって！？
How?
（ボーマ）
手本を見せてやるよ 新米
Let me show you, greenhorn.
（ボーマ）行け！
Go!
（バトー）ぐうっ！
とりゃああっ！
（兵士）うぐっ…
行け！ 少佐！
Major, go now!
I'm at the mid-level security bar.
（素子）
中層セキュリティーサーバーに到着
防壁のゲートアレイを確認
Confirm the gate array of the barrier.
軍情報部戦術防壁の亜種か…
It's a subspecies of the strategic
barrier used by army intelligence.
入り口だらけで出口が１つ…
面倒だな
There're numerous entrances
but only one exit. So much trouble!
（イシカワ）トンネル開通
I'll dig a tunnel. Damn it!
クソッ 中はナルデータだらけだ
It's all null data inside.
夜逃げされちまってる！
They escaped in the last minute!
（素子）既視感のあるフェイクだ
The null data is fake.
データはナルの向こうにある
The data is on the other side.
I'll find another way to get to it.
（イシカワ）回り道を探す！
I can't wait!
（素子）
もどかしい！ 私がこじ開ける！
Let me burst it open!
The active protect system of the data
transmission vehicle is damaged.
（イシカワ）中継車の
アクティブ･プロテクトが焼かれた
接続を切れ
Disconnect immediately!
もう遅いっ！
It's too late.
（ロジコマ）おわっ わっ
（パイロット）
何だ？ うわあああっ！
What is it?
（イシカワ）おいおい
いくつ隠しサーバー持ってんだ？
Hey! How many hidden servers are there?
（素子）丸腰で突入しないわよ
I won't break in unprepared.
コントロール奪ったわ 情報を
I've seized control of the ship.
I'll pass the info--
（素子）何だ これは？
what is this?
Signal 2, 6 and 7 are lost.
（兵士）
シグナル２ ６ ７ ロスト
艦内の敵勢力 現在位置不明
There're enemies on the ship,
their position is not clear.
（兵士）
射撃管制室を制圧された模様
Seems that the shooting control
room is seized by the enemies.
（バトー）とりゃあっ
（兵士）あっ…
（バトー）うりゃあっ
Great! Finally got it!
（バトー）よーし 捕まえたぜ
We're also done here.
（イシカワ）こっちも終わったぜ
Hmm?
Get down now!
伏せろ！
（バトー）もう１台だと！？
There's one more tank?
Mr. batou!
（ロジコマ）バトーさ～ん！
（ロジコマ）ストップ！
Stop!
（バトー）
コックピットは まだなのかよ！
Why's there still no cockpit?
（ロジコマ）申請中で～す！
We're still applying for it.
（素子）軍の再編？
Reorganization of the army?
なぜ私の部隊を…
一体 誰が？
Why is my squad... who did this?
そういうことだったの…
So this is it...
Escape now, major!
（イシカワ）早く逃げろ 少佐
（バトー）少佐 どうした？
Major, what's wrong?
おい 何がどうなってる？
Hey, what's going on?
（イシカワ）
コントロールは奪ったはずだ
She's seized control already, hasn't she?
誰かが近くから遠隔操作してやがる
Someone is near so they've changed
to control the ship remotely.
Saito, find those guys and finish them!
サイトー！
見つけ出して しとめろ！
（サイトー）もっと情報くれっ！
I need more information...
野郎っ！
Got it!
いい腕ね
You're really good at your job. If she dies,
彼女が死んだら 私が使ってやる
I'll employ you.
（サイトー）
クソがっ！ 逃げられた！
The guy has escaped!
Why aren't they chasing and attacking us?
（ボーマ）どうして俺たちを
撃ってこない？
船の奪還が目的じゃねえのか？
Their goal is not getting back the ship?
（素子）全員無事か
Is everyone alright?
（バトー）少佐！？
Major?
おおっ
（パズ）何だ！？
What happened?
You used the ghost infiltration key?
ゴースト侵入キーか？
（イシカワ）
強引に召集しやがった！
She's forcing us to gather together.
（素子）時間がない 手短に話すぞ
There's not much time so I'll make it short.
私は一定の仮説に従い
事件を洗い直す
I'll continue the investigation by
myself basing on a certain hypothesis.
There's no need for all of us to take the risk.
全員がリスクを負う必要はない
Major?
少佐？
データだ 本人じゃねえ
It's just data, not the real person.
（素子）
先ほど 部隊の解散を宣言した
I've just announced the dismissal of our team.
（トグサ･イシカワ）えっ！？
（パズ）何だって！？
Your reference letter is with chief aramaki.
（素子）推薦状を
荒巻部長に預けておく
転属先は自由に選べ
You can switch to whatever job you like.
お前たちは最高のパーツだ
You are the greatest 'parts'.
すべてがそろうことで―
When you guys get together,
私１人では達成しえない
パフォーマンスを発揮してくれる
you can achieve something much
greater than what I can do by myself.
That's all I have to say.
Follow your ghost.
（素子）以上だ
自分のゴーストに従え
Her cyber lobby is locked.
（イシカワ）ロビーを閉鎖された
So she's decided to purge herself out.
（バトー）
自分自身をパージしやがった
Maybe we are the ones who're left out.
（パズ）俺たちが切られたのかもな
So what's going on? It's not funny.
（トグサ）
どっちだろうと冗談じゃねえ
ぐっ… う…
ゴーストロックが効かねえ…
The ghost lock is not working...
う… ぐうっ… ううっ
（バトー）遠隔操作義体…
It's a remote controlled cyborg!
（北原）灘大佐は捕らえましたか？
Did you catch colonel nada?
審問の無期延期が不満ですか？
Is he dissatisfied with the indefinite
postponement of the examination?
私自身 何が本当か
分からないのです
I don't even know what's real anymore.
不満はない
He's not dissatisfied.
（素子）修理代は
商務省か極東通商部に回して
Ask the ministry of commerce (Moc)
Or eastern trade to pay for the repair.
別の車を貸してもらうわ
I'll need to borrow another car.
ファイア･スターター…
Fire starter...
Ls it originally the code of the virus?
そもそもウイルスの
開発コードなのか？
それとも お前の名か？
Or originally a name?
（ニセ素子）何か違いが？
What's the difference?
（桑原）要求どおり
情報艦は放棄した
We've given up the spy ship as per your request.
これ以上 何を望む？
What else do you want?
（ニセ素子）
肝心の草薙少佐が生死不明よ
The whereabouts of the key person
major kusanagi is still not clear.
そちらのネットでも捜索して
Please look for her in your network.
Your help is much appreciated.
協力しなさい
戦後最大のスキャンダルが
表沙汰になるわよ
We're about to reveal the biggest
political scandal after the war.
（荒巻）北原副大臣が殺害され―
Vice-minister of defense kitahara is murdered.
灘大佐は依然 生死不明
And colonel nada is still missing.
お前たちの事件は立証困難となり
捜査特権も失われた
It's very hard to prove that
what you said is true.
Plus your team has lost the authority
to investigate.
だが９課人員としてなら続行できる
But you can continue the investigation
as members of section 9.
Ha?
興味ねえよ
I'm not interested at all.
What?
（イシカワ）やってられるか
（トグサ）おい ちょっ…
Who would do this kind of thing?
お前ら それでいいのかよ！
Hey! Are you guys gonna give up like this?
どこからやり直したい？
Where do you want to start again?
If we can't get anything from the ship,
船から何も出ないなら―
look for those who refuse to testify.
関係者のうち
証言を拒む人物を探ります
（荒巻）
ロバート極東通商部代表か…
Do you mean Robert Lee from eastern trade?
手強い相手だ ９課のネットを使え
He's a strong opponent.
Use the network of section 9.
（トグサ）はい！
Yes!
Shoots have come out,
let's give it more time to grow.
芽が出て 多少育ったところだ
I won't let anyone destroy it... major.
潰させはせんぞ… 少佐
（イシカワ）ある情報があってな
I've got new information.
過去のデッドエンド回避策で―
The couple that's involved in the policy
義体開発者夫妻が消えたんだが…
to avoid cyborg development deadend.
Their corpses are kept in unit 501
調べたら遺体は―
501機関で研究用に
保管されているらしい
for research purpose.
The wife was pregnant when she died, wasn't she?
女房は妊娠中だったってんじゃ
ないだろうな
何の話だ？
What's this about?
ゼロ歳児の全身義体の話だ
About someone who's made a full cyborg at birth.
Are they major's parents?
少佐の両親？
（イシカワ）断定できねえのさ
There's no way we can confirm.
The corpses were too polluted for identification.
身元すら分からんほど
汚染された遺体だ
（バトー）
自分の体も持たずに生まれ―
Major was born without a body and
raised as a military equipment.
軍の備品として育った
失うものがないんじゃない
She has nothing to lose.
Coz she's never own anything that she can lose.
失うものを手にしたことがないんだ
She's been living like that before
（ボーマ）戦争が終わり
独立するまでは… か
the war ended and going independent?
Why did the victims who might be
（ボーマ）両親かもしれない
過去の犠牲者が 独走の理由だと？
major' parents have to run away?
（イシカワ）少佐のことだ
It was for major.
They must have found something big in their research.
もっとでかいもんを
追うついでだろうな
This is my thought. Major must've seen
俺の想像だが… 少佐は
あの船で何かヤバイものを見た
something dangerous on the ship.
俺たちをパージすると
決めたほどの何かを
Something so dangerous that
she has to purge us out.
Don't tell me she's trying to protect us.
I'll llaugh.
俺たちを守るってんなら笑わせるぜ
パーツ呼ばわりするくせに
She's the one who calls us 'parts'.
Though she calls us 'parts',
モノ呼ばわりはしても
モノ扱いはしてねえぜ
she's never treated us like 'parts'.
Anyway, being a full cyborg is full of 'parts'.
どのみち全身義体は
パーツそのものだ
組織に属してメンテしてもらうか
You either join an organization
to get support on maintenance,
生きながら朽ちてゆくか…
or rot away gradually as you live on.
（ボーマ）どこへ行くんだ？
Where're you going?
（バトー）
ゴーストに従うって柄じゃねえ
Follow my ghost, you know.
What I see is telling me to do so.
この目で見えるモノがすべてさ
船１隻 戦車２台 歩兵７人
One spy ship, two tanks and
seven armed soldiers.
えらく金のかかるワナだった
This trap must have cost a fortune.
What did she see?
何を見ていた？
話をしに来た
I came to talk to you.
（イシカワ）すんませんね
急に呼び出して
Sorry for the sudden visit.
情報部に戻りたいそうだな
I heard you wanted to return to intelligence.
草薙少佐の情報を渡せば
考えてやってもいい
If you'll give us information on major kusanagi,
I'll think about it.
話すのは てめえだよ
You are the one to give information!
私は…
I need to do my job as a messenger...
中継人としての役目を…
Kouichi sawada, ex-communication soldier
in the army panzer division.
（バトー）
澤田功一… 元陸軍機甲師団
昨日 所属不明の
情報収集艦で死亡した―
Your identity matches with one of the soldiers
国防派メンバーの１人と一致した
who's killed on the spy ship.
私は…
L.
（バトー）偽の記憶を
植え付けられたんですよ
Col. Haruyoshi nada, someone has
planted false memories in you.
灘 晴良大佐
Ishikawa! How could you do this
to your old teammate?
イシカワ 貴様―
古巣を敵に回して
タダで済むと思っているのか
You think you can get away with this?
痛覚を7,000倍にする
マイクロマシンだ
This is a micro machine that
can magnify pain 7000 times.
５分で電脳に到達する
It only takes 5 minutes to reach your cyberbrain.
我慢できるレベルじゃねえ
The pain's definitely not something you can bear.
（桑原）やめろ…
うっ… あっ… ううっ
Stop it!
やめろーっ！ うあああっ
Stop!
あっ… 中から！
Corning out from there...
Get in!
乗れ
（パズ）東亜連合幹部と
少佐の同型義体は―
The executives of southeast economic alliance
and that cyborg are allies.
最初から一緒にいたんだ
So we can't say the same party
attacked both sides.
両面同時テロの線は消えたな
お前は なぜ大使館に？
Why did you go to the embassy?
The gigantic electronic paper that was
found in the explosion site...
爆発現場にあった
特大サイズの電子ペーパー
そいつのデータを
断片だけ再生できた
I was able to recover part of the data.
（パズ）大使館の立体図？
A 3D map of the embassy?
まさか 総理の秘密会談の目的は…
The goal of the pm's secret meeting
is... that's impossible.
（桑原）
あの船は米国との密約で―
The spy ship is used for collecting
国内の諜報活動に使われていた
intelligence in collaboration with usa.
It's not for political scandals,
スキャンダルどころか
国防に関わるものだ！
it's for defence issues.
Why would they go as far as giving up
the spy ship to frame major?
なんで それを捨ててまで
少佐をハメた？
総理の敵は誰だ？
Who's the enemy of the prime minister?
総理は国防派を使って
商務省の造反組を退けたかった
The pm wanted to use the pro-mod gang
to curb opposition from moc.
それ以上は知らん
頼むっ 助けてくれっ！
That's all I know. Please let me go.
（イシカワ）フンッ
That's just vitamin, stupid!
ビタミン剤だ バ～カ
So it was colonel nada?
灘大佐本人だったのか…
末端兵士への同情が
疑似記憶をつくったのかもな
Maybe his sympathy towards front line soldiers
has created these memories.
本人の願望や罪悪感が
偽の記憶の核心となる… か
The wish or guilt of the person has
become the core of the false memory?
（バトー）そして
政府を脅迫するカードとして―
And then he got manipulated to
threaten the government.
生かされていた
This is unbelievable...
（荒巻）信じがたいことだ…
（トグサ）
ロバート代表は事件後―
Robert Lee later seized control of
リチャード大使の管轄だった
レアアース鉱山を独占…
ambassador Richard's rare earth mine.
They seem to be working together,
but actually they're in opposition.
表向き協調しながら
対立していたんです
戦争商売屋同士の潰し合いだ
So it's about military businessmen
trying to get rid of each other.
総理が大使を 代表暗殺計画に
加担させたのさ
The pm has requested ambassador Richard
to murder Richard Lee.
Then Richard Lee counter-attacked.
（トグサ）そして代表が反撃した
The broker has probably provided the
virus to both sides.
例のブローカーは
両方にウイルスを提供したんです
（バトー）天秤にかけたんだろうよ
The broker must've compared the
rewards and decided to take both.
そもそも これは 総理と
東亜連合の戦争だったんだ！
So this is a war between the pm and
southeast ecomonic alliance.
分かった
I got it.
少佐に逮捕命令が出された
An arrest order for major has just been released.
どこへ行く
Where're you going?
少佐ですら単独を選んだネタだ
It's something that even major would
choose to handle alone.
I don't think you guys are gonna have
the guts to do anything.
あんたらが動くとは
思っちゃいねえよ
わしを見くびるなよ
Don't underestimate us.
少佐は任せる 必ず生かせ
Please bring major back safely.
（バトー）フンッ
Huh.
（藤本）草薙少佐？
Major kusanagi?
ハァ… 君が現れたら教えろと
公安９課から言われた
Section 9 asked me to inform them
if I see you.
Do you want me to keep this meeting a secret?
彼らにも伏せたいと？
あなた次第です 藤本補佐官
That is up to you, advisor fujimoto.
（素子）敵が用意した爆弾を―
You are the one who sent the bomb
あなたがお父上のもとに
運んだんです
prepared by the enemy to your father.
（藤本）そんな…
How can this be...
もう１つ
One more thing. The discussion on a
私の部隊予算ですが
審議が一部不明でした
certain part of our budget is unclear.
Where did the money come from?
どこからの予算ですか？
（藤本）ううっ…
民営化される軍事部門…
It must be money left from
501機関という部署を解体する…
privatizing unit 501.
（藤本）余剰予算のはずだ
Please help me to restore my memory.
頼む 私の記憶を元に戻してくれ…
I can't stand to have this memory in my mind...
こんな記憶は耐えられない…
（素子）私は真実を選びます
I would rather choose the truth.
No matter how much I want,
どれほど心が願おうと―
I'd never trade my memory with a fake.
つくられた記憶に
替えようとは思いません
二度と…
Never again.
遠隔操作義体…
Remote controlled cyborg...
クルツ！
Kurutsu!
（素子）サーバーフロアに案内しろ
Bring me to the server floor.
Network for virus development...
（素子）ウイルス開発ネット…
外部送信？
External transmission?
（素子）攻性防壁に防壁迷路…
An attack barrier plus a barrier maze...
あなたたちが守るほどの
情報ってわけ
It must be something really important
that needs both of your to protect.
（ツムギ１）
懐かしい姿で認識されたな
We haven't been seen in this form
for a long time.
（ツムギ２）悪いが君を拘束する
I'm sorry but we have to stop you.
（素子）クルツの命令？
Is it an order from kurutsu?
（ツムギ１）我々全体の意志だ
It's a wish of us all.
（ツムギ２）
クルツは一部にすぎない
Kurutsu is only a part of it.
She's still alive, isn't she?
生きているのね
Please don't resist, kusanagi.
（ツムギ１）
おとなしくしてくれ 草薙
（ツムギ２）君を殺させたくはない
I don't want to make you kill.
ぐわっ…
（イバチ）そこまでだ
もうよせ 草薙
It's enough, kusanagi.
フンッ… はぐれ者が
You loner and loser!
ふんっ！
（素子）あっ！
どけーっ！！
Get out of my way!
This is your limitation, kusanagi.
それがお前の限界だ 草薙
（ロジコマ）少佐～っ！
Hello!
よお 起きたか
Hey, are you awake?
お前の隠しラボを
クラックして使った
We broke into your hidden laboratory.
文句言うなよ
Don't complain.
武器を内蔵して義体本来の性能を
落とすなんざ―
Hiding weapons in your prosthetics to
lower its performance is so not you.
お前らしくねえよ
（素子）なぜ来たの？
Why are you here?
隊長として命令はできねえ
Why didn't you say it like this?
だがゴーストを持つ人間として
一緒に来るか選ばせたかった
As the team leader I can't order you to follow me.
But as a person with a ghost,
素直にそう言うのはどうだ
I'd like to give you the option to go with me.
（素子）逃げなさい
Escape now.
お前が迷路から出たらな
I will, after you come out of the maze.
それまで俺たちの好きにするさ
Until then, we'll just do whatever we like to do.
（伊東）責任は取れるのだろうね
Can you bear the responsibility?
（ニセ素子）
心配ない 機関員を使う
Don't worry. We'll use government
officials to settle this.
（ロバート）
傘下の企業から兵士を出させる
I can send as many troops from our
subsidiary enterprises as you wish.
いくら消費してもかまわん
It's okay to have a huge number of
戦場並みに死んでもいいと？
people dying as in a war?
It's a business that's worth 500
billion dollars. We can't stop.
5,000億ドル規模のビジネスだ
やむをえん
After all, the idiots who want to change
the world are just minority.
世の中を変える気でいる愚か者は
所詮 少数派だ
速やかな排除が
君たちの民主主義だろう？
Getting rid of them quickly is
what you people call democracy, right?
フンッ
Don't resist, kusanagi.
（ツムギ１）抵抗するな 草薙
（ツムギ２）
君の脳を焼かせたくはない
I don't want to smash your cyberbrain.
（素子）私の防壁は
それほどチープじゃないわよ
My barrier is not as cheap as you think.
I didn't think she would attack our barrier.
（ツムギ１）防壁を逆侵するとはな
（ツムギ２）互いに戻れなくなるぞ
We'll all die if she doesn't stop.
その前に教えなさい
Then you'd better tell me before we all die.
クルツ本体の場所と目的を
Where's the real kurutsu?
What does she want to do?
（ツムギ１）場所は知らない
We don't know where she is.
彼女の多重義体は機密事項だった
Her possession of multiple prosthetic
bodies is top secret.
（ツムギ２）目的は変わらない
Her goal hasn't changed at all.
どの勢力が勝利しても
生き残るためだ
No matter which side wins,
she wants to live on.
分かってると思うけど
東亜連合の目的は―
I think you might know that
the goal of southeast economic alliance is to...
デッドエンドによる技術革新と
市場独占よ
Innovate prosthetic technology and
monopolize the market.
（ツムギ２）まだデッドエンドを
迎えていない子供たちがいる
Many kids can still upgrade their prosthetic body,
it's not a deadend yet.
彼らを企業の商品にする気？
Do you wanna sell them to enterprises
as commodities?
（ツムギ１）
すべてを託すべき後継者だ
They have inherited hopes and
dreams from all of us.
They'll become next-gen prosthetics.
（ツムギ２）彼らが次世代型となり
長期的バージョンアップを実現する
They can have upgrades in the long term.
そうして
同じことを繰り返させるの？
Do you want them to repeat the same thing?
And to sell their ghost?
ゴーストまで売り渡して
This is...
この～！
You've always been free.
（ツムギたち）
君はいつでも自由だった
（ツムギ１）
常に未来を創ろうとする
Always wanting to create your own future.
（ツムギ２）そんな君が羨ましいよ
We really envy you.
私を守って…
You two are protecting me...
（ツムギ１）
どのみち 私たちの脳は限界だ
Our cyberbrain is our limit anyway.
We'll shift to the third world before
we meet our deadend.
その前に第三世界へシフトする
We hope to become a part of
the sea of information.
（ツムギ２）データの海の一部に
なることを祈ってね
Maybe some day we can connect with you again
（ツムギたち）
いつか君にアクセスする存在が―
in a new form of life.
生まれるかもしれないぞ
Is it there?
（素子）そこかっ！
（バトー）サイトー！
Saito!
（サイトー）
野郎 ふざけやがって！
Damn it! Don't mess with me!
ぐうっ！
Is everyone still alive?
（トグサ）みんな生きてるか！？
If you die you can't be repaired.
（ロジコマ）
死んだら修理できませんよ～
（バトー）いい男は死なねえんだよ
A good man like me doesn't die easily.
（バトー）うりゃあっ！
うりゃあっ！
Why are you standing here like a log?
（素子）何を突っ立ってる
If this is your level of performance,
I'm gonna purge you out.
そんなパフォーマンスなら
交換するぞ
フンッ これから
見せるとこだったんだよ
I'm just about to show you what I've
got, gorilla woman!
メスゴリラ
があっ ああっ
うっ… ぐうっ！
（パズ）少佐！
Major!
（イバチ）ハァ…
You stupid loner!
はぐれ者がーっ！
Are you alright, major?
（トグサ）少佐 無事ですか！
（ライゾー）うりゃあっ！
Normal prosthetics are the best, right?
ノーマルな義体が一番だろ？
逃げろと言ったはずだぞ
I thought I've told you to escape.
You bunch of stupid festival lovers.
お祭り好きのバカどもが
I don't think I'll ever find...
お前たちのようなパーツは―
'Parts' like you guys.
二度と集められないんだぞ
We still have some important work to
finish, haven't we?
まだ大事な仕事が終わってねえだろ
What's going to change after
you arrest me?
（雨形）私を逮捕して何になる？
The same game will just repeat after
内閣解散後
同じゲームが行われるだけだ
the dismissal of the cabinet.
Some ministers who'd stepped down
also said the same
引退する何名かの大臣も
同じことを言っていたが―
but I disagree.
そうはさせない
We use money and technology to
resist wicked systems and business.
（雨形）
私たちは金とテクノロジーで―
悪辣(あくらつ)なシステムに対抗してきた
And you guys use guns.
君たちが銃を握るのと同じだ
我々は犯罪を憎むが―
We're just doing the same thing.
No, we hate crime. But you create
criminals for reaping profits.
あなた方は利益のために
犯罪者を生み出す
One day you will understand.
（雨形）いずれ君にも分かる
そこにいたの…
She's there...
You're late. She's about to leave.
（管理人）遅かったな
もう旅立つ頃だ
（素子）クルツ！
Kurutsu!
Kurutsu is dead.
（クリス）クルツは死んだ
Even though the same prosthetics is used,
同じ義体を操っても
二度と同じ人格として振る舞えない
the character won't be the same.
Even myself feels strange.
自分でも不思議だ
When did you start doing this?
（素子）
いつからそうしていたの？
From the beginning.
（クリス）最初からだ
I've been using micro machines to fix
the incomplete growth of my body.
成長不全を
マイクロマシンで補い―
Since I couldn't be prosthetized,
義体化できない代わり
多くの義体を動かしてきた
I've started to use multiple prosthetics.
なのに お前の名だけは
名乗れなかったな
But no matter what I do, I can't seize
your body and name.
How about fire starter? Did you develop it?
（素子）ファイア･スターターは？
開発したのは あなただったの？
You'll understand some day.
（クリス）いずれ お前も分かる
情報のパッケージの多様性と―
The variety of packaged information
and the birth of a new world.
新たな世界の誕生を
I'm going to that place where everyone is.
私は そこへ行く
みんながいる場所へ
You are freer than anyone else.
（クルツ）
誰よりも自由だったお前が―
It's a pity you have to stay in a world like this.
こんな世界に残ることを
あわれむよ
Were you able to say goodbye to her?
別れの挨拶はできたかね？
Why did you use her?
なぜ彼女を利用したの？
Cyberbrains and prosthetics...
電脳と義体 それが陥る―
Are the two possibilities in avoiding
デッドエンド回避のための
２つの可能性…
the deadend of prosthetic development.
Which is you and her.
それが君と彼女だった
It's just that simple.
それだけのことだ
Take him back.
（荒巻）連れていけ
Please stop searching for the names of the dead.
（管理人）死者の名を探すのは
もうやめたほうがいい
You won't find anything.
得られるものなどない
As someone who's lived as a dead
man for a long time,
長年 死者として
過ごした者の忠告だ
that's my advice.
What is it?
（素子）何だ？
You are not taking us?
（女の子）
連れていってくれないの？
Where should we go...
（男の子）僕たちはどこへ行けば…
（素子）何が望みだ
What do you want?
Do you want to sell your body and
ghost to get a standardized cyborg?
体とゴーストを売って
統一された規格を得ることか？
Sacrificing those who don't have
与えられなかった者たちを
犠牲にして
the chance to get it?
お前たち全員 電脳がある
All of you have your own cyberbrain.
従うべきゴーストを持っている
You have a ghost which you should follow.
Stop expecting to get from others,
それ以上を他人に望み
代わりに何を差し出す気だ？
think about what you can give.
Create your own future.
未来を創れ
The framework of the government
（伊東）いわば政府の建前で
我々の貿易とも矛盾しません
does not conflict with our trade.
If the slave countries are slow in serving,
（ロバート）結構…
奴隷の国が奉仕を怠ると―
the rich ones will feel hungry.
貴族の国は飢えますからな
Shortage of labor will only encourage slavery.
（伊東）人手不足は奴隷業を潤す
Are we really doing this, major?
（バトー）本当にやるのか 少佐？
Head of eastern trade plus secretary
（荒巻）極東通商部代表に―
商務省の伊東次官殿と
組合幹部か…
ito from moc and other officials?
You...
（ロバート）貴様…
Mfa and mod are also watching.
（荒巻）この様子は
外務省や防衛庁も見てる
We'd like to invite secretary ito to
help with our investigation.
伊東次官には審問に出ていただこう
総理暗殺の件で供述してもらう
About the murder of the prime minister.
We're doomed.
（伊東）終わりだ
That won't happen.
His petition for political asylum
不可能だ 彼は亡命を希望し
受諾され―
has been approved.
宣誓書にもサインした
When did that happen?
いつだ！？
答える義務はない
I have no obligations to answer.
The document is in the embassy.
I'll forward it to you later.
書類は大使館にある
後日転送してやろう
There'll still be people carrying out
orders of the ex-prime minister.
前総理の意思は生きている
暗殺されるぞ
You'll be assassinated.
Isn't this country a civilized
and pacifist nation?
（ロバート）フンッ…
ここは平和主義の文明国だ
Is it?
（素子）あら そう
窓の外だ！
Outside the window!
Help me!
（伊東）助けて～！
Stop it!
（荒巻）やめっ！
It's nice to view the sakura together.
みんなで花見ってのもいいですね
This is also work.
（素子）これも仕事だ
（トグサ）えっ？
Keeping the sakura under surveillance
24 hours a day.
（素子）桜の24時間監視というな
Major, I've got work for you.
In south Newport--
（荒巻）少佐 仕事だ
南新浜(みなみにいはま)４区で…
no way.
嫌よ
Your budget's approved. Start working.
（荒巻）予算は通した 仕事をしろ
Logicoma!
（素子）ロジコマ！
Yes
（ロジコマ）は～い！
審査会予算通過レポートを
確認しました！
I just checked the report on the
approval of our budget.
（素子）よし！ 桜の監視は中止
Good. Stop watching the sakura.
Let's
出るぞ！
you are the best 'parts' I've ever found.
（素子）お前たちは私が手に入れた
最高のパーツだ
Perform to your best and get the job done!
パフォーマンスを発揮し―
事件を取れ！